# Katherine Eaton

Hamilton, Ontario, Canada

□ (+1) (905) 512-3057 | 🗷 ktmeaton@gmail.com | 🌴 ktmeaton.github.io | 🎓 Google Scholar



2014 - Present

2019 - 2021

2017 - 2021

2017 - 2018

2013 - 2014

Hamilton, Canada

### **Summary**

Katherine is a multidisciplinary researcher, bridging the gap between the sciences as a computational biologist, and the humanities as an anthropologist of infectious disease. As a senior PhD candidate, she is occupied with writing papers, giving conference talks, and supporting laboratory training and facility operations.

#### Education

**McMaster University** Hamilton, Canada

PhD in Anthropology

- 2014 Present • Plague Phylogeography: Novel Synthesis and Geospatial Analysis
- Dr. Hendrik Poinar

**University of Toronto Mississauga** Mississauga, Canada

**OPEN STUDIES** 2013 - 2014

- Coursework in Computer Science, Mathematics, and Bioinformatics.
- · Dr. Esteban Parra

**University of Alberta** Edmonton, Alberta

**B.A. IN ANTHROPOLOGY** 2009 - 2013

- Evaluation of bodeterioration in deer bone inoculated with Amycolatopsis sp. using SEM.
- Pamela Mayne Correia

## Work Experience \_\_\_

McMaster University Hamilton, Canada

MASTERS-TO-PHD FAST-TRACK STUDENT (DEPT. OF ANTHROPOLOGY)

- Provide undergraduate-level course instruction and assessment (ANTH and BIO).
- Provide graduate-level training in laboratory techniques and computational analysis.

**McMaster University** Hamilton, Canada

RESEARCH ASSISTANT (McMaster Ancient DNA Centre)

- · Bioinformatic Analysis.
- · Manuscript Preparation.
- · DNA Extraction, NGS Library Prep, Bacterial Genome Sequencing.

**Lewis & Ruth Sherman Centre for Digital Scholarship** 

GRADUATE RESIDENT

• Software development for high-throughput genomic analyses.

**MacData Institute** Hamilton, Canada

GRADUATE FELLOW

- Formation of the new McMaster Digital Pedagogy Working Group.
- Graduate Colloquium presentation, community building.

**University of Toronto Mississauga** Mississauga, Canada

VOLUNTEER (DEPT. OF ANTHROPOLOGY) • Annotation of genes associated with pigmentation in East Asian populations.

**University of Alberta** Edmonton, Canada

Undergraduate Thesis Student, (Dept. of Anthropology) 2012 - 2013

· Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) of bone.

KATHERINE EATON · RÉSUMÉ JULY 19, 2021

University of Alberta Edmonton, Canada

2011 - 2013

VOLUNTEER, SUMMER STUDENT (DEPT. OF SURGERY)

- Molecular biology assays and cell tissue culture, DNA sequence analysis.
- Immunodetection of genes involved in skeletal development.

# Public Output \_\_\_\_\_

#### PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATION

2020	A Black Death mass grave at Thornton Abbey, Lincolnshire: the discovery, Co-Author	Journal
2020	NCBImeta: efficient and comprehensive metadata retrieval from NCBI databases, Author	Journal
2019	Genetic resiliency and the Black Death: No apparent loss of mitogenomic, Co-Author	Journal

#### **PRESENTATION**

2021	Plague phylogeography: Novel synthesis and geospatial analysis, Presenter	Podium
2020	Presenting "The Plague": Digital exhibits as interdisciplinary method, Presenter	Exhibit
2019	Digging into digital anthropology: Project-based learning, Presenter	Podium

#### SOFTWARE

2021	Automatically create release notes and a changelog, Developer	Github
2016	Efficient and comprehensive metadata acquisition from the NCBI databases, Developer	Github

# Honors & Awards \_\_\_\_\_

#### RESEARCH

2019	HASTAC Scholars Fellowship, \$600	International
2019	Sherman Centre for Digital Scholarship Bursary, \$500	Hamilton, Canada
2018	Anthropology Graduate Conference and Travel Competition, \$600	Hamilton, Canada
2012	Undergraduate Research Initiative, \$250	Edmonton, Canada
2012	Collective Body for Arts Students Individual Grant, \$500	Edmonton, Canada

#### ACADEMIC

2019-202	McMaster Graduate Bursary, \$3400	Hamilton, Canada
2016-2019 Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Doctoral Scholarship, \$105000		Hamilton, Canada
2017	MacDATA Graduate Fellowship, \$7500	Hamilton, Canada
2015	Canadian Graduate Scholarship Master's Program, \$17500	Hamilton, Canada
2014-2017	7 Anthropology Graduate Scholarship, \$16000	Hamilton, Canada
2013	University of Toronto Advanced Planning for Students Grant, \$5000	Mississauga, Canada
2012	Erindale Bursary, \$800	Mississauga, Canada
2010-2012	2 Suncore Energy Scholarship, \$3000	Edmonton, Canada
2009-202	1 <b>Jason Lang Scholarship,</b> \$4000	Edmonton, Canada

# Committees & Service \_\_\_\_\_

2019-2021 <b>Fellow</b> , HASTAC Scholars	International
2019-2020 <b>Co-Founder</b> , McMaster Digital Pedagogy Working Group	Hamilton, Canada
2018 Conference Executive Chair, Rewriting Plague: History Meets Science	Hamilton, Canada
2017-2018 <b>General Member</b> , President's Advisory Council for Building an Inclusive Community	Hamilton, Canada
2016-2018 <b>General Member</b> , European Association of Archaeologists	Hamilton, Canada

JULY 19, 2021 KATHERINE EATON · RÉSUMÉ 2